Hi, I'm Amelia and I'm going to talk to you about ways to prevent hair breakage.
First let's talk about what causes hair breakage.
When the hair's wet, it's in a weakened state, also chemical services can cause your hair to break.
Anything that actually weakens the bonds of the hair can cause your hair to break.
So, when your hair's wet, you don't want to consistently pull it up.
You also don't want to constantly be combing your hair roughly when it's wet.
When it's wet, you want to use your comb, and lightly comb from the bottom up.
Remember, hair is a fiber, just like silk.
Some hair's like silk, some hair's like denim.
So, figure out which one yours is like and treat it as such.
When you put a pony tail in, you want to make sure that you don't use a rubber band.
You can use something like this, they are like rubber bands, but they're specifically for hair.
They slip out of the hair, where as rubber bands tend to grab at the hair, because they're rubber, a little bit more less slip, so the hair grabs and rips.
This is a lot silkier, so it doesn't grab.
When you are coloring, you want to make sure that any time you color and you're retouching anything, you don't want to bring that color back over, it's called overlapping.
You don't want to overlap that color.
So, if you're trying to re-touch some roots, you don't want to bring that, I wouldn't want to bring that brown all the way up, or I wouldn't want to bring this lightener all the way down.
I'd want to just do the spot that I needed to do, and leave the rest out, because the more you color something, the more it breaks down the bonds, the easier it's going to be to snap.
So, as long as you're gentle with your hair, as far as combing, coloring, and if you're really concerned, you can do maybe monthly protein treatments, and that will help with the strength of your hair.
And just make sure not to brush it too hard, when it's wet it is in a weakened state because it can stretch, so it only stretches to a certain point, and then it snaps.
So just be gentle with your hair when it's wet, and that will all help you prevent your hair from breaking.